<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Automate on David Just</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/tags/power-automate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Automate on David Just</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/power-automate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Data from workstations and send to an Excel Table for free</title>
      <link>/post/power-automate-send-data-from-powershell-to-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/power-automate-send-data-from-powershell-to-excel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;/post/power-automate-send-data-from-powershell-to-excel/powerautomate.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          Premise There are times when I encounter a situation where I want to gather some data from workstations and store it in a spreadsheet / table ect. for tracking purposes. Recently I was working with a client to deploy a cloud printing solution. The on prem print environment was somewhat complex with multiple shared printers some of which were locked down to AD security groups. I needed a way to get a pre-deployment printer inventory for each workstation, then compare a post deployment inventory.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collect data in an Azure Table with Power Automate and PowerShell</title>
      <link>/post/create-power-automate-flows-with-powershell-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/create-power-automate-flows-with-powershell-reports/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          If there is one thing I love it is automation. If you are a systems administrator, you have probably at some point needed to create some reports using PowerShell. Usually you would do this manually and export this to a CSV them hand off the report in an email or through SharePoint ect. But how can we automate this process?
While you could run PowerShell scripts as a scheduled task to fire off an email which is quick and dirty.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>